Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
No living creature was harmed during filming
this series
Episode 81
Osman.
Don't.
So you don't want to die.
But
In my tradition...
...we don't show mercy to the cruels.
Run fast!
Bring me the weapon!
My Bey!
Let's cut them down!
Alps!
Do not shed the blood of brothers!
you
My Bey, we try, but there is no
end of them!
I will not stop until they end then.
Thank that they are falling off one by one.
The rest are making our work hard enough!
My Bey!
Osman will surely catch who did
this and make them pay, mother.
He is busy with them right now.
If Osman's plan goes as planned
He must have killed the Vizier by now.
But
If something goes wrong about
the cemetery plan...
There will be a large number
of soldiers ready to strike them.
Then we will go and support
Osman Bey.
We shall wait for the news.
Mother.
Mother, you are fine, Thank Allah.
Thank Allah
I'm fine
Osman.
Is there any news about Osman
We will receive news, Inshallah, mother.
Selcan Hatun, thanks be to God
You are fine
She's fine, she's fine.
My mother is a strong lady
She is Selcan Hatun!
Good news will arrive soon,
Inshallah (if Allah permits)
Inshallah (if Allah permits).
Let's finish them!
So that we can
take care of the Vizier!
My Bey, they must be the last soldiers
in Sogut.
This Osman will be up to something.
We must be careful.
You are going to
build a sheltered place in this room
A shelter behind walls
It must be absolutely complete.
There will be no shortage.
Your order, Hadrat Vizier.
Cerkutay!
My Bey!
Tie them up!
Your order, my Bey!
-Your order, my Bey!
- Come on!
You fight well, Kosses.
Look
There are guys better than me.
Praise be!
You are with us now
But if you come out as our enemy later...
You see what might happen.
Eyvallah (sure).
Kutan, Seran!
Valiants, come on
tie up these soldiers.
Your order, my Bey.
Why don't you kill us, Osman Bey?
I don't kill Turkish soldiers who think
they are fighting for their country
because of a traitor leader's command
My problem is with Vizier
who has deviated from the truth.
That Vizier betrays Sultan
You will see this too!
But...
Your souls are safe with us now.
You still need to keep calm meanwhile.
Eyvallah (okay) Osman Bey.
Be good!
Cerkutay!
We won't kill them but...
We can beat them a bit.
We'll get out of here before dawn.
But first...
I will see Vizier Alam Shah.
If we can't get out...
You know what to do.
My Bey!
Vizier is absent!
What are you saying?
Stay with the soldiers, Alps!
Vizier!
You ran away like a snake
He can't jump from here
while injured, can he?
If he had jumped, we'd see his body now.
I know the wound my sword caused!
Why didn't this guy die then?
Coward Vizier!
He wore armor inside his clothes then!
So he saw that coming, huh?
- Baysungur!
- My Bey!
Look around, see if there is any trace.
Your order, My Bey!
Cerkutay!
- My Bey.
- Search every inch! Hurry!
Hurry!
Inegol Castle
No mistakes.
No mistakes this time.
None!
Did Lord ever sleep?
Sleeping, Julia?
My castle was given to the shepherd Gunduz,
that old dog is telling me what to do...
I can't sleep under these circumstances!
If I was an idiot...
I could sleep.
Just maybe I could.
I thought that your agreement
with Vizier would satisfy you.
Yes, when Vizier was forced
to agree with me.
But all things changed with the coming of
Geyhatu, Julia.
Even though their offer
seems like an opportunity...
With that devil Geyhatu...
...is involved...
I must have a third eye
at the back of my head!
Otherwise, my back...
My back will turn into
a stage for goals like this, Julia
Geyhatu.
You seem to know him well, Lord Nicola.
If I kill you all...
All lands were left to Osman...
If I make him Bey of the Beys....
Wouldn't it be great?
Tell me.
Geyhatu!
If you go down
to the well with his rope...
He'll strangle you with that rope.
We are ready for your orders, sir!
The sun is rising.
Prepare your soldiers, Argos.
We'll depart.
Your order, sir!
Lord Nikola!
No matter where you go...
I'll be by your side, you should
know that.
Osman!
I will destroy you, Osman
Sogut
Commander Geyhatu!
Vizier Alam Shah is in Osman's hand.
Osman wounded him.
I will take your soul Osman!
Alam Shah!
I thought you were smart!
You are so stupid that you
fall into the hands of Osman!
We'll kill Osman here.
Here in Sogut.
You are somewhere here, Vizier!
You are definitely somewhere here!
You are somewhere here!
Well, what if
he really jumped off the balcony?
Osman Bey says look for him in the inn,
there must be something he knows
He thinks he's in the inn.
He sent his Alps out for him.
That means he is not fully sure.
What is the harm
of hard work, Kosses?
Let's find this dog, help me!
Let's find him, let's do it.
Come on.
Turgut!
Vizier Alam Shah!
You won't even die on your honor,
but run away like a rat
Hide wherever you want!
I will find you and take you out!
Alps!
Search everywhere in detai!
He must have left a trail behind!
My Bey!
There is no trace outside, my Bey!
But... Geyhatu...
Geryhatu
encircled outside the inn.
What are you talking about?
Damn it!
What is Geyhatu doing here?
This is not good Osman Bey.
It's not good at all.
He sent his soldiers to the cemetery.
His only concern is to see Vizier here.
Alps!
Find that Vizier
and bring him to me right away!
Bring him so that...
I can lay his corpse in front of Geyhatu!
Come on!
Your order, my Bey!
Come on, Alps!
Can I, my sheik?
My sheik.
Soldiers of the Mongols, Sheik...
Mongol soldiers are attacking
Sogut, my sheik.
Will you allow us to arm ourselves
with swords, my sheik?
We haven't been armed with a sword
in the khanqah until now.
Now it's time.
Osman is in the inn.
The great Geyhatu will take him.
Do not try to help Osman.
Whoever helps him...
...they will die.
It is the truth that determines our life.
Your words are of no importance,
not even an iota.
The outskirts of your khanqah
besieged by the Mongol soldiers
If someone wants to die now...
they can peek outside.
Apparently it was the Vizier
who brought Geyhatu to these lands
We don't know what's really going on.
As they came here...
They are aware of the existence of Osman
in Sogut.
What do we do now?
Do you think Osman killed Vizier?
There is no news about them at the moment.
But the Mongols know they are in the inn.
Bala Hatun.
I want to fight too.
You stay with my mother, Zehra.
Calm down, Bala.
Being idle like this bothers me, Malhun!
Enough!
Osman, my sheikh,
their lives are all in danger!
If we go now, we can't help them!
Mongols are everywhere!
We have to think of something else, Bala!
You are right, Bala.
Waiting is so annoying.
But you should think of your child first.
Enough.
Instead of giving birth to my child
under the shadow of the cruels...
...I prefer death!
Get out of my way.
Prepare your swords.
But keep your hearts calm.
My Bey.
Geyhatu's aide is coming!
He's coming armless.
He obviously doesn't want war.
He will vomit the poison that
falls from Gikhato's tongue.
Let him come.
Osman Bey.
Talk.
Commander Geyhatu wants you.
He is waiting for you to talk to him.
Geyhatu will not leave you alive,
Osman Bey.
Do not go.
Turgut is right.
If we all get out of here together...
...we might have a chance.
But if you go alone...
We can't protect you then.
No.
Since the soldiers of the Mongols did not
break the door and attack us until now...
Geyhatu knows that
Vizier is in our hands.
He won't do anything because we have him.
But...
Alps!
The inn is ours!
The property is ours!
That Vizier won't get out of here!
Until I come back from Geyhatu...
...tou will spread his corpse here!
Your order, my Bey!
Osman Bey.
Be careful just in case.
I came all the way to
fight with you, my Bey!
Let me join you.
No
I'm not going to fight.
It's a duel of words.
You search for the Vizier
with the alps.
Your command, my Bey.
Osman!
Fear the end I will prepare for you!
You will die begging!
Vizier!
Vizier is a coward!
He must have built
himself a secret hideout.
Whether it is in the wall or underground!
We will take him out of where he hides!
I'll make you all go through hell,
every one of you!
I will survive.
I will not die.
Blood, blood, blood!
Osman.
You are in my hands again.
I'm on my own land.
You are in Sogut.
Your land's future is up to my sword.
I am able to ruin your lands.
I would not keep you as a captive.
I would destroy the castle
and plunder the city!
I would cut off your head!
Of course,
this happens if you don't surrender.
It is clear that your intention is not
making me give up.
Your intention is to take Vizier
safe and sound.
He serves your dreams.
But...
...about the Vizier...
I have no intention of killing him
right now.
I want to kill him slowly.
You will give me Vizier Alam Shah!
You will surrender!
You have no other chance.
We have always a chance.
Everything has a solution.
Goktug was talking like you when
I took him as a hostage.
I cut his heart!
We can't let Geyhatu's soldiers
to wander around us, my sheik!
My sheik, we should fight
and get Osman Bey out of the inn.
Geyhatu's soldier informed us just now.
Osman Bey decided to talk to Geyhatu.
What are we going to do now,
my Sheik?
We'll stand in silence...
...and waiting for Osman Bey's move.
If required,
we kill those outside and get to the inn.
Osman.
We were dragged into an empty cemetery.
There is no funeral!
Vizier Alam Shah!
I'm afraid he may be hurt.
You are right.
We have to find Vizier Alam shah at once.
Hurry.
Don't say my brother's name
without permission!
I know the games you and the vizier play!
You deceived my brother and
made me lose my throne!
You arranged an attack on the Sultan
And you accused me of all this!
You have caused the bloodshed
of so many innocents and valiants!
You will be held accountable for all of this!
But first...
But, first that Vizier.
And then your turn will come too.
The rebel Bey of the border regions, Osman!
His tongue is as sharp as his sword!
You like peace.
Do not cause bloodshed
Give me the Vizier and surrender.
All of you will continue living.
If you don't surrender,
I will burn Sogut down.
Geyhatu.
Surrendering to the cruels
is dishonorable for us.
You never change, Osman.
If I find you even after fifty years...
you will be the same man
and have the same stubbornness!
Not fifty years
even if a thousand years have passed...
The Turkish will be the Turkish himself
And his blood is the same blood!
Our determination will not vanish!
Have you seen, brother?
He doesn't hide his words even from Geyhatu.
- Praise be to my Bey!
- Praise be, my Bey.
Yes, Bey is a braveheart.
Boran Alp, we didn't notice you.
Brothers, I am here or not,
what's the difference?
Here is Osman Bey who is standing
on the field like a lion in the face of Geyhatu
Praise be!
I wish all of Kayi alps were there.
You want to die so badly.
You will drag down your alps and people!
You are crowded.
We are Turks.
None of my warriors will fall
before killing ten of your soldiers.
Blood, blood, blood!
Is that so?
Brothers! My Bey is coming!
Assuming that you are back safe and sound,
Geyhatu is really asking the Vizier.
You were right.
We will fight until our
last drop of blood!
It's time for war!
War is a feast for us, my Bey!
Show us the target, let us strike!
Oh the joy of our souls, my Bey!
I'll meet my brother Goktug and Bamsi Bey.
Command us to die, my Bey!
Command us to go out and fight, my Bey!
Even if my religion
is not the same as yours...
Fighting on the same side with
such honorable soldiers honors me as well.
Let's go and fight Osman Bey!
Eyvallah Kosses, Eyvallah (Thank you).
My Bey, we searched everywhere
but there is no trace of the Vizier.
He is somewhere here.
He's wounded.
If he does not come out,
he'll die in the hole he hides in.
Kayı's Alps have always managed to
get rid of the enemy.
We always have!
What are the alps of Osman Bey will do?
Look, the Mongols are
beating the drums of war!
Should Osman Bey's alps
stay idle...
...while Osman Bey is in a
difficult position?
Of course we won't stay idle!
We are with our Bey.
Praise be to my brothers!
Inform the alps of Kayi.
Today is the day of shahada.
- Come on!
- Eyvallah (okay).
Today is the day of shahada.
Allah Allah!
My Lord, whoever trusts you,
do not leave them alone.
My sheik, we won't leave
Osman Bey there.
O Almighty.
Allah is Amlighty.
He prevents whoever he wants...
..protects and sends help.
Help us my Creator!
- Amin.
They are raging my sheik!
They want blood!
Let's go and bleed them!
We will not hold our swords back
from the cruels.
We will not leave Osman Bey there!
Can I come in?
Mother.
My sheik.
My Osman will take care of himself.
But his son Orhan..
He is alone.
We have to think about him first.
Mongols might want to take Orhan
to corner Osman.
Mother.
You are making me worried!
May Allah protect him!
Also, Gündüz Bey is with him Mother.
I no longer have confidence in Gündüz.
His eyes are blind to the truth
and his ears are deaf.
Also, he must be coming here when he hears
You are right, my Bey.
It's easy to abduct Orhan
while Gündüz Bey is in Sogut.
We'll go and take Orhan with Aygül.
We'll get him and
come back right away, mother.
Akca Dervish, send two dervishes
with Malhun Hatun.
It's hard for me to leave you here while
Mongol dogs are outside.
Don't think about us.
Orhan's life is priority.
Come on, go get him at once!
My Sheik.
Go, daughter.
Mother.
May your path be open, my daughter.
- May your fight be holy, my sheik.
- Go now, daughter.
And now, it's our time.
Come on.
Oh Allah, protect my children
and the whole Kayi tribe
We are ready to burn Sogut,
Commander Geyhatu.
Attack!
For bloodshed!
Brothers!
My valiants!
May our conquest be blessed!
Eyvallah my Bey!
My Bey!
Kayi Alps...
They rain arrows on
the Mongol soldiers!
Praise be!
We are walking behind the Kayi Bey.
Come on, all to work!
Come on alps.
Alps!
Allah is the greatest!
Allah is eternal!
Allah is right!
Allah is the greatest!
Stop your soldiers, Geyhatu!
Impudent Gunduz!
You need your soldiers.
And I need my brother.
Stop, don't let any more blood shed.
Osman said his word.
We will fight.
And I'll cut off his head!
Geyhatu! Listen me!
I am the ally of the Vizier of Seljuk State
Trust me!
I'll convince my brother.
Soldiers!
Stop!
Hurry up, Gunduz!
My patience is running out!
Convince Osman.
Otherwise, I will demolish Sogut
over your heads!
Osman Bey!
I am listening.
Won't you surrender?
Are you going to let everyone die?
Martyrdom.
Since when did martyrdom become death?
But this happens because of
your stubbornness, my brother!
No it's not.
Our heart is never satisfied to
be a slave to the Minister like you.
Ask them!
Ask them, my brother!
Did you get your answer now?
Gündüz Bey.
Who trapped us here?
Who helped Vizier claim Sogut?
Tell me!
Well, what about my mother?
What about my mother?
You should pray that...
...my mother is alive.
If anything had happened to her...
I would kill you with my hands.
Banishing my wives from the tribe!
Separating my son from his mother!
What does this mean?
Tell me, what does it mean?
Yes.
This is the kind of thing that
a Bey like you would do
Open your eyes.
Open your eyes brother, open them!
You were about to involve in
my mother's death!
And now you stand in front of me!
And you tell me to surrender!
I care Alps!
I care you!
You say you care me,
yet you burn my heart!
You say you care the tribe,
yet you burn the tribe!
Brother, Vizier blinded your eyes...
deafen your ears.
Vizier is in my hands.
I will kill him slowly.
Don't do it brother.
Don't destroy us.
Notice the reality!
The reality is in front of you
and you ignore it!
The reality calls for you to notice it!
You don't hear!
Go get judged by Konya.
Acquit yourself from those accusations.
Games and hatred surrounded that justice.
Only sentence...
...is my sword!
Bilecik Castle
We will have such important
guests today, right...
...my dear friend?
Bilecik's chefs had already
started to work.
They will prepare us a magnificent table.
What table, what guest, Nikola?
Besides, you still haven't given
me an answer.
Why are we in Bilecik?
Is it true what happened to Lord
Rogatus?
Rogatus!
He is paying the price for his betrayal.
That's all.
I heard the Seljuk Vizier
took over the castle.
You should've asked the Vizier before
calling the other Lords here.
His turn will come too.
Don't worry.
But first...
...I have a greatly advantageous offer for
you and the other lords, my dear friend.
I don't know.
I listened to you and came here.
No, Nikola.
I won't be at this dinner.
My dear friend...
... the truth is...
...the main dish of this dinner's
menu is...
...the lands.
But if you keep insisting
that you will leave...
...you'll be deprived of the main dish.
You said well.
You said well, my brother.
You hit my mistakes one
by one in my face.
Thank you.
Now you face me as if...
...you had done nothing, Osman.
What Vizier said were slanders...
...fine.
Why did you escape from them, then?
You threw our tribe into a fire!
You tell me that I exiled the hatuns.
Who provoked them and set them on me?
You tell me that I stole the throne.
Right?
Who left the throne, Osman Bey?
If there is a fire in Kayı...
...you are the one who set it!
How can one that is afraid of burning...
... shine, brother?
When did a Bey ever step back?
Did my grandfather Süleyman Şah
ever step back?
Did my father Ertuğrul Gazi
The road was hard and...
...you knew it, brother.
You knew.
Why did you let me down?
Why?
I didn't leave you or Kayı alone!
Do you think I don't have
the same dream as you?
For that dream, my brother...
...surrender.
Surrender so that the dream can come true.
That dream doesn't come true by bowing
to the devil!
They tried to kill the Sultan and blamed
it on me.
I know you wouldn't try to kill
the Sultan, Osman!
Then why are you on their side, brother?
So that they won't ruin us, Osman!
So that they won't destroy us, Osman!
If one of us weren't on their side...
...there would be no Kayı...
...or no tribe, Osman.
I had to.
If you know everything...
...then go tell Geyhatu that...
...I will never surrender.
Let him try his best!
All right, brother.
Brother!
Master Geyhatu, Nikola gathered the lords.
He is clearly up to something.
Nikola is smart. He understood that I will
take his castle his lands.
Take your men! He will be beheaded before
he returns to his castle!
Are you all right, my Vizier?
No one saw you, right?
I didn't, don't worry.
Geyhatu and his soldiers are outside.
But neither Osman nor his alps are in
the tavern.
Osman!
Immediately inform Geyhatu that Osman is
not in the tavern.
How could I leave you alone, my Vizier?
You are wounded.
Inform him at once, Celali.
I am fine. I will get out of here
by myself.
He doesn't listen, does he?
He doesn't.
Your brother is a rebel.
He doesn't listen to his elder.
I listen to Argun.
Rebels like him are doomed to be crashed.
Do you have anything to say?
Are you going to protect Osman who tried
to kill the Sultan?
Get out!
Geyhatu!
Let the siege continue.
Hunger and thirst will surely...
...make him surrender.
Protect your soldiers.
And I will protect my alps.
It is done, Gündüz.
Get out. Don't end up like Osman.
Alps!
Let me end up like my brother!
I won't let one of you go without
killing me!
Stop! Stop!
Osman...
...is not there. He escaped.
Vizier Alemşah is alive.
Find Osman!
Burn the tavern down!
Burn the Söğüt down if necessary!
Osman has escaped!
Find him!
Thankfully!
Osman!
Search everywhere!
Vizier Alemşah!
Where did Osman escape?
Soldiers
Find me the way Osman used to escape!
Osman!
I am glad if Vizier Alemşah died.
But if he is alive, we leave here now
so that...
...we can kill him.
He has no chance of surviving.
He can't live with that wound for long.
You did what's best, Osman Bey.
Otherwise, everyone would get hurt.
You saved Söğüt, my Bey.
Also, we killed many tyrants, my Bey.
If the oppressor persists in
his cruelty...
...his end is near.
Victory is near if the one on
the right path...
...persists in the war
Now we will live to be their executers.
Come on! We are going to Çoban!
Come on!
Osman!
One of Osman's man's blood, Geyhatu.
-They escaped from a secret passage.
-What are you waiting for?
Find him, now!
Find him!
Get out!
I will go too.
It is my duty to avenge Vizier Alemşah.
Go. Get me Osman's head!
Where are you going, Ferman?
You must stay with Vizier Alemşah.
Celali is enough for my Vizier.
We need more soldiers to kill Osman.
What is this, Master Davut?
Master Davut...
...it is clear that...
...you do your duty properly.
We are on the job, my Bey.
Tell me, Master Davud...
...tell me...
...how many swords did you make?
I made as many swords as
the lives of infidels...
... that you took while you were away...
...my Bey.
Praise be!
Great job.
Thank you, my Bey.
I guess I couldn't understand.
Isn't the Söğüt under the control
of the Vizier?
Do you think we let go...
... every time we get into trouble,
Kosses?
The swords aren't made in Söğüt.
It is...
...this love of conquest...
...that keeps me alive...
...in these difficult times.
We spoke with Master Davut before.
Until the heart stops...
...forging hammers will never stop.
Thank you.
You say nice but...
...what if you weren't able to get out of
that tavern, Osman Bey?
Then, it would be left to Orhan.
Rogatus is here, my Bey.
Osman Bey, Kosses!
You are still alive!
You too, my old friend!
I brought you crucial news
from Constantinople.
I can tell.
Tell me, Rogatus.
The Emperor is furious!
He found out that Geyhatu came.
He makes too much sound.
He is mad that the lords are
looking for...
... other things while there is
the Mongol danger.
What is he planning to do?
He will gather...
...all his trusted commanders...
...in the Sagoros' Castle.
He will go there secretly.
Good.
I hope the Emperor Andronikos...
...he is tolerant of unexpected guests.
Since, I will be there too.
We need more soldiers to stand against
Geythatu.
My troop has already arrived
at the castle.
We will take them with us too.
We are stronger together, Osman Bey.
My alps are also always ready for war.
But are these soldiers enough, Osman Bey?
Let me give you good news!
Do not let the native Montenegrins...
...be destroyed!
Don't let the rough tree be cut down!
Don't let the splendid water
flowing like blood dry up!
May your wings don't break!
May fate not make you needy!
Don't let your white-brown horse...
...stumble while running!
Praise be!
Soon, my Orhan.
Soon.
It is soon that you meet your parents
again.
If you keep quiet, my Orhan will meet
his parents, Ayşe Hatun.
Malhun Hatun!
How did you get in?
I came to take my Orhan.
I wish to take him easily.
Come on, give me my son.
He belongs to his mother.
Don't I know.
I am a mother.
Also, Orhan missed his mother very much.
Come on, take your son.
My son!
Aygül.
Thankfully!
Let's go.
The alps are changing guard.
Be careful.
I worry about you.
Don't worry, Ayşe Hatun.
Two alps are waiting for us outside.
Let's go to Osman Bey, Aygül.
Let's go.
Let's reunite them.
Wait.
Cover him with this.
May my Allah protect you.
Come on.
I will wipe out Osman's lineage!
Edebalı...
...you will be punished!
I will fill up the lodge with your blood!
I will drown you in that blood!
Calm down, Geyhatu!
I will talk to Sheik Edebalı.
It is no longer the time to talk, Gündüz!
It is time for them to pay!
I will burn Söğüt down!
Geyhatu! I will call my soldiers anytime
I want!
Leave the lodge and Söğüt alone!
You need us!
Am I stuck with your weak horse...
...your unarmed soldier, Gündüz?
Geyhatu, I have the strongest horses!
I have the most valiant of the soldiers!
Don't make a mistake by succumbing
to your anger.
You need me.
The more you talk the angrier I get!
I don't want to talk anymore, Gündüz!
You will join my army with a thousand
horses and a thousand soldiers.
Get out!
Watch the tribe and the lodge!
Find Osman wherever he is!
Sure, Master Geyhatu!
Where is he!
Find him!
Kill him!
Soldiers!
I never trusted you, Konur.
I knew you would betray.
You are just following the order.
Get off your dagger or
I will have to hurt you.
Vizier Alemşah loved you, Konur.
He will be upset.
Not everyone gets enough time to choose
the right side, Ferman.
We are in this world to serve Allah
and surely we will return to Allah.
Soldiers!
Retreat!
Let's go find Osman!
First, we need to find the tracks.
Tracks.
We have to find my Bey
before those dogs do.
We shouldn't be seen together.
What we are going to face is unclear.
Eyvallah, you are right.
Then let's get you dressed.
Come with me, come on.
Did Vizier teach you not asking for permission
before entering the khanqah, Gündüz Bey?
Stop there!
Are you still talking, Akca Dervish?
You tested me with my mother's pain!
You said she's dead!
While the Mongols had been raiding
Sogut because of Osman's stubbornness, right?
What do I have to tell you anymore?
Don't say anything, Gündüz Bey.
You haven't talked sanely for a long time.
Do you know what I had to do
to protect you, my sheik?
Geyhatu had taken an oath to
destroy the Khanqah.
Do you know how difficult it was
to talk him out of it?
Don't you see the situation that
you put me in, my sheik?
I would prefer dying to
obeying the cruels!
I wish you had joined
in our case of righteousness...
But you trusted the fake
with the fear of losing your life.
You may consider me as wrong.
My Allah knows my attention.
If you insist on not listening to me...
I'll do things I don't want to.
Just for the sake of peace of Sogut.
Can I, my sheik?
What more are you going to do,
Gündüz Bey?
Are you trying to go beyond yourself?
Give me patience, my Allah!
You won't do anything without
telling me anymore!
Those things you do on your own...
....throws the whole Sogut into the fire
What kind of brother are you?
You don't see us, understand us!
You are still accusing us.
May my Creator show you mercy.
Where is my mother?
I will see her.
Mother doesn't want to see you!
Is Rogatos on our side just to
go to the Emperor?
Tell me!
Are you with us in the war?
I...
I don't really know what to think of
this union which is consisted of old enemies.
I'm a Lord.
I still have two loyal commanders.
Two commanders means two
great troops.
I will order them to join you.
You realize how big this case is,
my friend Rogatus.
Yes, we get it.
What about your commanders?
Do they realise how big this is?
They will fight for Turks for the first time,
not against them.
You are talking about men who would
rather die than surrender to the Mongols.
Uniting with Turks is not
worse than death.
However...
Guarantee their loyalty.
I hold you responsible for
the simplest mistake they make
There will be no error.
We will gouge out the eyes of those who
set their sights on our lands.
I hope we don't have a
conflict afterwards.
Time will reveal that.
We have to get out of this trouble first.
Someone is coming.
Go to your commanders, Rogatus.
Do not move.
Do not touch.
There may be another trap.
They noticed at the right time.
They had time.
Otherwise...
Untie them.
Untie them, let's see who they are.
My Bey.
These are the heroes
who saved us that day.
They protected us earlier.
My Bey.
Boran.
It's done, my Bey.
My Bey.
Brother!
Are you fine?
Thank Allah, my Bey.
Brother.
Konur?
what are you doing here?
Tell me why you came.
I saw the truth, Osman Bey.
What made you see...
...the thing you didn't see earlier?
Tell me.
That Vizier tried to kill Hatuns.
And you hid your face and
helped Hatuns.
Right?
I want to be with you from now on.
Konur.
We don't have hot food like Vizier offers,
neither a comfy bed.
We don't have a place that offers food.
Our food is here what
the shepherd gives us.
A heart gains strength
as it faces hardships.
It regresses as it faces easiness.
I am with you, Osman Bey.
The wound on my back is still there.
What about yours?
It may not heal the wound I caused, but...
I brought you some important news.
Geyhatu heard that Nicola
gathered the Lords.
And he sent his soldiers to kill him.
Why now?
Why?
I thought I was serving the truth
I realised I was following falsehood.
While I was saying that you are a rebel
I found out that I'm with the rebels.
Tell me everything you know.
It's hard to keep Geyhatu down.
We made a mistake to invite him.
It's like fire approaching to oil!
He can burn down these lands.
That's why you are in such a great power!
Keep Geyhatu under your power.
The destiny of these lands
is in your hands.
Therefore, every solution is permitted.
We can even agree with Pope...
...if it comes to that point, Alem Shah.
Keep that in mind.
We will do what must be done.
To ally with Pope, ha?
Oh my God.
Even I wasn't expecting all of this.
Vizier surprised me.
He's trying to do something
bigger than him.
We can't even imagine Vizier's betrayals,
Kosses.
To reach the top position...
He can do everything, even risk
his life and everyone under him.
Since when has he been meeting
that guy?
They talked a few times.
I only saw it once.
Argun Khan sent 20 thousand soldiers
for Geyhatu.
They want to take Turkish rebellion
under control.
However...
The goal of Geyhatu and Vizier
is to destroy us.
Do you think Nikola knows that?
Is this why he gathered the Lords?
I don't think so.
But he is doing the right thing.
Now that you are on our side...
...then...
Stay with Vizier for a while.
Bring me information from him.
Information is everything.
Command is yours.
My Bey.
We'll take Nikola from Geyhatu's hand.
- To kill him yourself, right Osman Bey?
- No.
I need Nicola for now.
How do you need him Osman Bey?
What are you saying?
Let those dogs eat each other.
We know what he did to Mari!
Nikola!
We are talking about Nikola.
My Bey, he is involved in every trouble
we face!
Do it Osman Bey.
Do it.
When the dogs eat each other.
A stronger dog comes out of them.
Keep one by your side so that
you have the power to deal with the other.
I don't have a throne to sit on
There are not enough alps to win.
Enemies are like the sand on the desert!
That's why...
...To protect these lands...
I need Nicola.
Do not worry at all!
We will never forget what he did!
We will surely hold all the cruels
accountable!
And certainly when an innocent looks
back to see if there is anyone with them...
They will see us.
This is my last word.
Eyvallah.
Come on.
Sogut.
Can I come in, Vizier?
Enter.
Hadrat Vizier, you have a guest.
Do you allow him to enter?
Let him.
Welcome.
Sorry to hear what happened, Alam Shah.
I brought my Bey's blessings.
My Bey is very upset
about your health.
Thank him very much.
We are walking on the way of our
sacred case thanks to him.
We all are wounded for him.
We all suffer for his dreams.
Eyvallah. (thank you)
And we heard that Geyhatu
saved you by besieging the inn.
The punch of a relative is
better than the bread of a stranger.
I don't want the help
that will come from the Mongols.
Our intention is to save
this land from their oppression
We hope to expel
the Mongols and the infidels
And become the supreme state.
Just like when it was in the era of
Aladdin Keykubat
Osman is pursuing the same goal.
Osman Bey is very brave.
But he's a little guy.
What is his knowledge? Is he a statesman?
What is his educational attainment?
His grandfathers are shepherds,
and his ancestors are as well
He cannot create a state.
He is a Bey who takes care of sheep
and sleeps in a little tent
He shouldn't see too many dreams.
A land cannot have two leaders.
Kill him as soon as possible.
If only he knew when to obey.
I would make him a commander
of my army.
And now he's poor,
his head will be cut off
Son.
Dear Orhan.
May Allah let me see the days
that you ride horse and hold a sword!
Amin.
Be brave and always be on the side of
the truth and those with the truth.
- Amin.
Who knows, maybe you are thinking
why we are not in our tents.
I will warn you and your future brothers
and sister about....
....those munafiqs (fake believers)
like Vizier.
They...
They tried to set brothers against each other
in the past, and they do it now as well.
They won't stop in the future.
Their faces and names will change.
But their betrayal will not change.
Son.
There will always be enemies around you.
However...
As long as there are such
brave brothers by your side
No one will be able to defeat you!
And the great state
will advance on your shoulders!
Inshallah my Bey.
Alps!
Tomorrow is the time for war!
We will waste the hopes of the Vizier
and Geyhatu
- As you order my Bey.
- As you order, my Bey.
Say what you want to say, Geyhatu.
I'm here, Gündüz, I came.
Dear friends.
Geyhatu and the Vizier
want to wipe us off this land.
These men can't stand
anything about great Rome.
This is for sure.
Rogatus, Kosses.
Traitor Kosses.
They didn't deserve to be a Lord!
If they are not present
in the presidency of their castles...
...those castles are not anyone's, right?
Isn't that right?
I mean, we have to stand firm in front of
the Vizier and Geyhatu.
But, Nikola, I can't spoil
my relationship with Geyhatu for no reason.
I agree, both are very dangerous.
Real danger...
...is that they'll try to end us forever!
Can't you see that?
Today Harmankaya and Bilecik!
Tomorrow, Yarhisar! Inegol!
And all our lands one by one! If you don't
want to be erased from history forever...
We have only one chance!
We unite!
Our castle, our words!
We have to claim
Harmankaya and Bilecik again.
We owe this to great Rome, all of us!
- Aren't we?
- It's true what you're saying, Nicola.
You are right, Nicola.
So, Nikola...
How will this happen?
How will we get the castles back?
In the best way we know
By shedding their blood.
And if necessary, shed our blood
- Via war!
- Via bloodshed!
- For Rome!
For Jesus Christ!
That's it!
Standing up together!
Sir, Osman...
He escaped from
Geyhatu and Alam shah.
As you see...
There is Osman as well.
My dear friends.
Trouble never leaves this land.
We have only one solution
And that is to unite.
I'll go back to my castle
tomorrow morning.
And after I do all my preparations...
We're going out on the road to
Harmankaya from different places.
Why didn't we wait for
Alam Shah to recover before talking?
If we wait for that,
they will also heal their wounds.
The first one to stand up again
will win the war, Gündüz.
Nicola.
He'll die.
Inegol is ours now.
And then we'll take castles
of other Lords and their castles.
And then?
Is it our tribe's turn next, Geyhatu?
What can I take from your tribe?
No need to use force.
You will give me soldiers, horses
and supplies when I want.
Castles and fortresses will be yours.
You are the only ruler in
border areas, Gunduz.
Talk!
When we got out of the passage,
we were rained with arrows.
All soldiers died.
Why didn't you die?
Did Osman do this to you?
I couldn't see.
Where is Konur?
Where is Ferman?
They are dead.
Damn it!
Mingiyan.
Kill Nikola.
Never fail again.
By your order, Geyhatu.
Go!
How can you give
Orhan to Malhun Hatun, Ayse?
How can you let them go?
Sogut is boiling now!
How do you throw my nephew
in danger, Ayse?
Malhun Hatun is the mother of Orhan,
Gündüz, how was I supposed to say no?
Do you think that she doesn't care
her son as much as you do?
If she cared about her son, she wouldn't
question the order of Bey!
She wouldn't deserve exile!
Don't defend Malhun Hatun
What should I do?
Do I defend you against you?
Should I defend the Vizier?
They slander your brother,
you believe it, Gunduz!
Shall I tell you
well done?
Your mother and sisters are in danger!
You don't do anything
Do I give a pat you on the back?
The Mongols have entered Sogut,
Gündüz Bey!
You still listen to what Vizier says.
Should I tell you, well done?
What do you want me to tell you Gündüz?
Is enough
I don't want to hear even
a single word, Ayse.
Ayse.
I will burn the whole world down
for Orhan, Ayse.
Gunduz.
Have you ever seen a happy child
while being away from his mother?
Unless you cancel this exile...
Malhun Hatun will not
bring Orhan to the tribe.
I cancelled it already, Ayse.
I already did it.
I can't leave my nephew there, Ayse.
Also, if I can't protect my mother and
sisters while they are away from the tribe...
I shall have them with me.
I know they are not going to behave,
we'll conflict, but...
But I have to hit a happy medium.
I just want Orhan with us.
I just want my mother and sisters
to be safe.
I entrust you to Allah, my sheik.
If we don't go to the tribe now, we will
have betrayed the entrust of Osman Bey,
Taking care of the entrusts is
what you should do, my precious daughter.
Our return will be for the best,
even if it's Gunduz Bey's call, my sheik.
Thank Allah my mother is healthy again.
Thank Allah so much.
Gunduz Bey made a mistake.
He is now trying to make up
for that mistake.
Other than that,
Orhan will be safer in his tribe.
You are right, my Sheik, but...
I can't trust Gunduz Bey.
This may be a trap.
Only Allah can know the inside
of hearts, my beautiful daughter.
We will take measures just in case.
Let's hope Gunduz Bey's intention is pure.
Inshallah, my sheik.
Inshallah.
I entrust you to Allah.
I do as well.
I am grateful for what you did.
And you're one of
my daughters now, Mari.
I entrust you to Allah.
Sure, she's our daughter now.
She listened to us, married
a Turkish Bey.
May the other girls do the same as well.
Inshallah.
Let's go then,
my Sheik.
Go.
Mother.
Rogatus, our way seperates here.
Your way is to Iznik.
I will be waiting for you in Nikea,
Osman Bey.
I hope you save that stupid Nikola.
Eyvallah!
Your path shall be open!
Do not draw your weapon.
Otherwise, Mary will become a widow
And what do they call a brotherless woman?
- I will...
- Marie became my wife
Watch your movements.
I'll make you pay for
what you did to Mary.
Nicola.
Harmankaya is mine!
Come on!
Soldiers!
Attack!
I worked so hard to prevent this, but...
Because you followed Osman's stubbornness...
Many misfortunes have befallen us.
Thank Allah no one was hurt.
You are in the tribe now.
We are in the tribe to take care of our honesty
Gunduz Bey.
I won't bother myself
explaining your mistakes to you.
What's the point of explaining to
someone who doesn't understand?
He swore not to hear you.
You are right, Bala Hatun.
Nobody knows those people
better than me.
Keep that in mind!
You are my sisters...
You are my brother's entrust.
But whoever is trying to break up the tribe...
They should know that...
I will stand against them as long as I am
the Bey of this tribe
Whoever tries to divide the tribe...
I will punish them myself.
Boran, are you okay?
I'm fine my Bey!
Mongols on one side,
Turks on the other side!
Hell with you all!
Take him.
- Commander Geyhatu a messenger arrived.
- Let him come.
Arkun Khan...
Is it...
What is written, Geyhatu?
It says that a good deal of soldiers
are on their way to this land.
Argun Khan sent twenty thousand soldiers
under my command!
To put down the rebellion in the tribes!
I...
Vizier...
I will kill everyone!
Osman Bey!
Your effort to kill me...
...must be appreciated.
I will not give you to anyone
Your death will be at my hands
At my hands!
Death knocked on my door a lot of times,
Osman Bey.
But none of those attempts succeeded.
Don't trust your luck too much.
You will die
But...
I will kill you in such a way that...
...not today
When you caught
a relentless enemy like me...
Won't you kill me?
Today...
...there is no friend or enemy.
We will move together to stay alive.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com